<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Pomaville</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew Pomaville</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Presentation</title>
      <link>/projects/final-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/final-presentation/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project - Women and Children First?</title>
      <link>/projects/final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/final-project/</guid>
      <description>Final Project Graph - Titanic Women and Children Introduction This graph looks at the common maritime trope “Women and children first” in the survivors of the sinking of the RMS Titanic on its maiden voyage in 1912. It is commonly believed that men on the Titanic took a role ensuring the women and children on board made it onto the lifeboat before boarding themselves, resulting in more women and children surviving the sknking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a graduate student in Kevin Wright&amp;rsquo;s lab at the Vollum Institute at Oregon Health &amp;amp; Science University. My primary research interests are mammalian sensory nervous system development and patterning.
I completed my undergraduate degree in Biology as a member of the Smittcamp Family Honors College at California State University, Fresno. While at Fresno State I worked with Dr. David Lent researching the role of the central complex in invertebrate spatial learning and memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Graph - Nathans Hot Dog Eating Contest</title>
      <link>/blog/first-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first-graph/</guid>
      <description>About the Data This plot was created using ggplot2 and other tidyverse packages in RStudio. The data to generate this plot was originally collected, cleaned, and hosted by Jackie Wirz, Steven Bedrick, and Alison Hill here and was modified by Matt Pomaville. The final data set used can be found here
The data used in this plot was collected from the Nathan’s Hot Dog Eating Contest website and Wikipedia page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Graph - How has the MOMA gotten its paintings over the years?</title>
      <link>/blog/fourth-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fourth-graph/</guid>
      <description>This graph looks at the number of gifted paintings vs the number of paintings acqired through purchase or exchange by the MOMA grouped by decade.
Type of Graph This graph is a stacked column graph.
 The Data This data came from a pre-cleaned version of the Museum of Museum Art data set generated by www.fivethirtyeight.com. It was cleaned by Alison Hill and further modified by Matt Pomaville. It is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Graph - Global GDP per Capita 1952 vs 2007</title>
      <link>/blog/second-graph-global-gdp-per-capita-1952-vs-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/second-graph-global-gdp-per-capita-1952-vs-2007/</guid>
      <description>Change in GDP per Capita graph brief This is a brief describing the graph created from the gapminder dataset. It is available as a CRAN Package by installing gapminder and calling library(gapminder) during setup.
Load required libraries To make this graph I used the tidyverse, gapminder, and wesanderson libraries.
library(tidyverse) library(gapminder) library(wesanderson)  Cleaning up the gapminder data The gapminder dataset is gigantic and because for this plot I was only interested in the 1952 and 2007 data I filtered for only that data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Graph - Are all continents approaching the global mean life expectancy?</title>
      <link>/blog/third-graph-are-all-continents-approaching-the-global-mean-life-expectancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/third-graph-are-all-continents-approaching-the-global-mean-life-expectancy/</guid>
      <description>Life expectancy by continent vs. global mean life expectancy graph brief This is a brief describing the graph created from the gapminder dataset. It is available as a CRAN Package by installing gapminder and calling library(gapminder) during setup.
Load required libraries To make this graph I used the tidyverse, gapminder, and wesanderson libraries.
library(tidyverse) library(gapminder) library(wesanderson) In this visalization I want to examine the relative number of countries in each continent with life expectancies over themean life expectancy in 2007 by year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Pomaville a graduate student at OHSU in the Cell and Developmental Biology Graduate Program.
This website is currently a demo site for CS631, but will expand at a later point.
Here are some example graphs I created for CS631 along with descriptions of what they show
Here is my final project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>